<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GCP on Matt Wang's Note</title><link>https://mattwang44.dev/tags/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in GCP on Matt Wang's Note</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mattwang44.dev/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Preparation of GCP ACE Certification (2020)</title><link>https://mattwang44.dev/2020/07/01/gcp-ace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattwang44.dev/2020/07/01/gcp-ace/</guid><description>Go to this article for the note of the Coursera course Cloud Engineering with GCP After sailing through the storm with my company (thank you COVID-19 &amp;#x1f635;), I decided to have a two-week off studying GCP ACE exam on my own and leave all the things behind. I&amp;rsquo;ve passed the exam in late June of 2020 and got the certification . This article records how I prepare for the exam and those awesome reading materials I&amp;rsquo;ve found.</description></item><item><title>Course Note: Cloud Engineering with GCP on Coursera</title><link>https://mattwang44.dev/2020/06/15/gcp-ace-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mattwang44.dev/2020/06/15/gcp-ace-note/</guid><description>This is the note of the course Cloud Engineering with GCP . Go to this article to see how I prepared for GCP ACE exam.
Mind Map GCP Network Resources VPC Network Subnet IP Load Balancer HTTP(S) SSL Proxy TCP Proxy Regional Multi-Regional VPN &amp;amp; Peering &amp;amp; Interconnect Compute Services Compute Engine (GCE) Disk type persistent HDD/SSD Local SSD Instance template Instance group App Engine (GAE) Standard Flexible Kubernetes Engine (GKE) Cloud Function Storage Data warehouse BigQuery Database NoSQL BigTable Cloud Firestore Datastore mode Native mode Relational Cloud SQL Cloud Spanner Redis/Memcache Cloud Memorystore SDK &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;gcloud&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;gsutil&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;bq&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; Stackdriver Monitoring Logging Debug Error reporting Trace Big data services BigQuery Cloud Dataproc Cloud Dataflow Cloud Pub/Sub Cloud Datalab SDK Cloud SDK installation and quick start gcloud tool guide &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;gcloud&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; command &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;gsutil&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; command &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;bq&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; command Resource Management Resource Hierarchy Global Images Snapshots Networks Regional External IP addr.</description></item></channel></rss>